VERONIKA HARBACHOVA

Austin, TX 78701 | 734.834.2893 | veronika.har@hotmail.com

Profile Summary

Linguist turned web developer blends soft skills of adaptability and openmindedness with hard skills of web development. Cross-functional collaboration with tech teams and successful experience of working as a part of one. Have developed a flexible, empathetic communication style that serves as a compliment to the technical rigor required to excel as a coder. Experienced multi-lingual and cross-cultural project manager that listens first and enjoys translating business requirements into technical capabilities.

Experience

Staples (PNI Media) – Austin, TX, USA

Frontend Developer | 02/2020 – now

- Tech stack: React, Sass, Typescript, Redux, Ajax;
- ✓ Working in SAFe Agile environment.

Freelance Web Developer – 12/2018 – 02/2020

- ✓ Portfolio website: https://veronikaharbachova.netlify.com/;
- ✓ Github account: https://github.com/VeronikaHar;
- ✓ 15+ projects using React, Node, Vue, vanilla JS etc. including collaboration;
- ✓ A project example: a movie web app that requires users to create an account to access information on movies, directors, genres, add/remove favorite movies to the profile, edit/delete their account info. The app uses RESTful API. Front-end done with React, Redux and Bootstrap. Back-end done with Node and MongoDB.

Generation_P – *Minsk*, *Belarus*

XSLT developer / Assistant Team-Leader | 09/2007 - 08/2008

- ✓ Achieved full technical competency in 3 months without any prior experience (CVS repo; PAROS (POST/GET); Oxygen+Eclipse; XML etc);
- ✓ Assistant Team-Leader supervised team performing patch-and-release responsibilities and negotiated business solutions with foreign customers.

Education

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development

CareerFoundry | 01/2019 – 11/2019

- 300+ hours of training/mentoring with industry leading Front-End and Senior Full-Stack Web Developer.
- Intensive project-based training program with a focus on JavaScript, HTML, CSS and most prominent libraries, frameworks and tools;

Master of Arts in Linguistics

Dalian University of Technology | 09/2008 - 07/2011

Bachelor of Arts in Linguistics

Belarusian State University | 09/2003 - 06/2008

Skills

React.js

Redux

React Native

Node.js

jQuery

JavaScript

REST API

HTML/HTML5

CSS/CSS3

PWA

Bootstrap

Responsive Design

TDD

Toolkit

NPM

TypeScript

Sass

Jest / Enzyme

MongoDB

Heroku

CodePen

Git / GitHub

Google Analytics

Google Tag Manager

Chrome Dev Tools

Photoshop